<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other on Krzysztof Kondrak&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://kondrak.github.io/categories/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other on Krzysztof Kondrak&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 23:47:58 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kondrak.github.io/categories/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing jobs and careers after a VERY long time</title>
      <link>https://kondrak.github.io/posts/2024-01-14-changing-careers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 23:47:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondrak.github.io/posts/2024-01-14-changing-careers/</guid>
      <description>There comes a moment in most IT specialists&#39; careers when at one point they sit down and start re-evaluating their personal and professional goals and asking themselves: &#34;What is it that I really want to do?&#34;. It&#39;s a thing a lot of us experience for the first time early in our lives, while still in school or university. At that age, you want to plan ahead and figure out your entire path for the next 40+ years of your work life, then make a choice and go for that job where you spend, hopefully, many long and fruitful years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coincidence, luck and getting my first job in gamedev</title>
      <link>https://kondrak.github.io/posts/2016-12-11-coincidence-luck-and-getting-my-first-job-in-gamedev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 18:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondrak.github.io/posts/2016-12-11-coincidence-luck-and-getting-my-first-job-in-gamedev/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  I recently hit a milestone in my professional career &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s been exactly 9 years since I made a move into games industry. This may not sound like something profound or significant but the circumstances of my transition from regular software development were rather interesting. I think it&amp;#8217;s fair for me to say I was quite lucky and found myself in the right place at the right time. Today I want to share something I always bring up when talking to students or people who want to get a job in games REALLY bad but don&amp;#8217;t know who to ask or how to start. This is the story of how I unintentionally and accidentally started making in games.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching is hard</title>
      <link>https://kondrak.github.io/posts/2016-11-24-teaching-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 23:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondrak.github.io/posts/2016-11-24-teaching-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Even though it&amp;#8217;s been many years, I can still remember my first days in school after I started education as a little kid. I truly admired and looked up to teachers who, to me, were the living embodiment of knowledge. I think I was really lucky because I was taught by people who truly had the calling and for a brief moment I even wanted to become a professor myself. However, as the years passed on, I developed a feeling that I would not make a good person to share what I know with others. My patience was low and I found it tremendously difficult to discuss things that were obvious to me but a novelty to others. Becoming a teacher turned into a nightmare job for me and I quickly realized this is something I want to stay away from as far as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with LinkedIn tech recruiters - 3 simple steps</title>
      <link>https://kondrak.github.io/posts/2016-05-08-linkedin-tech-recruiters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 22:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kondrak.github.io/posts/2016-05-08-linkedin-tech-recruiters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  It&amp;#8217;s that time of year again &amp;#8211; recruiters on LinkedIn are starting to send out messages and job ads faster than anyone can read them. This is something I think every tech person experiences after spending substantial amount of time registered there. What suprises me is that a vast majority of people I know despise getting this kind of mail which, at the first glance, seems contradicting to the purpose of being on a professional social network. While different people may have different reasons to being registered on LinkedIn, I seem to have a rather unpopular approach of treating it as an opportunity to possibly land my next job &amp;#8211; something that happened to me before, twice. With that being said, I accept all contact invitations unless the account is clearly recognized as spam or completely unrelated to my line of work (and that doesn&amp;#8217;t happen very often).
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>